I understand what I'm supposed to do, so why can't I move forward?
I feel like I have no reason to win, so why is it so painful when I lose?
No matter what I do, I fail, it's useless.
Oh
He's staring. He's totally staring at me
He's huge
scary
Hey, um, so what's your name? Oh
Oh
My name's Ray. Oh
What's your last name? Uh, my last name? It's Kiriyama. Why? Oh
I thought I recognized you you became a pro shogi player while still in middle school. It's so nice to meet you
I'm Yusuke Takahashi
Huh?
Here's the thing. I'm a baseball player and one day. I hope to become a pro in the big leagues
Now I didn't know back then. I mean if I should go to a local high school with a sponsorship
Or if I should go to a rural school that has a chance at entering the national championship
So my dad showed me an article about you
Out in the world there are people like him this kid decided what he wanted and went for it
He's in middle school and already a pro shogi player if you want to be a pro you've got to muster up the courage and make your own decision
So I finally decided to go to a high school in Shikoku a coach who helped me out at a junior tournament invited me to join his team there
But I have a question for you
I've been wondering a year after becoming a pro shogi player. You went back to high school, right?
So why did you decide to go back there?
I
His expression was so serious
Knew this was a question that needed more than the superficial answer it required a sincere response. I
Knew that much
But
How could I get it across to him?
Well, you see, the truth is the only thing I've ever really been any good at is shogi. I'm not comfortable socializing, and I do like studying, but I never really fit in at school.
I
Decided to go pro at a young age, and I have no regrets
But
I think I wanted to have memories of not running away
No more running
I'm totally embarrassing myself
Wait, what am I even saying?
Why am I telling all of this to a middle school kid? I don't even know
I see
What?
I get it
I used to think about the fact that I'd run away or slacked off in the past
So sometimes I'd freeze up at the plate, and then my coach would tell me that I have to believe in myself
But if you've ever wanted to run away, it's tough, especially remembering how it feels
Like, you can't help but think about when you've messed up and the times you've failed
Believing in yourself is hard
I'm sorry, I'm not sure what to say
But that's kinda what you're talking about, right? Believing in yourself?
I'm not sure what to say
But that's kinda what you're talking about, right?
Believing in yourself?
He gets it
Mm-hmm
Oh man
What's this feeling?
I think I'm... happy
It felt like...
If I let my guard down
I would cry
Tears would stream down my face
I was relieved
I was so happy
He understood me
Oh
Hey Takahashi
I'm sorry we were late
Are you ready?
Yeah
Hold on just a sec
Can we do this again?
Yeah
We should try and talk again soon
Yeah?
You sure?
Definitely
You can get in touch with me again through Hina
Oh, cool
Okay
Then I'll give you a call later Hinata
Yeah, sure
Sure
Worn out
Thud
I don't believe it
Thanks, Hina
Takahashi's a really cool guy
I know, right?
He's pretty mature for his age, don't you think?
So?
What did you two talk about while I was gone?
I wanna know
Huh?
Well...
So stuffed
My time has finally come
Thanks, that was great
Alright then
There
I was able to make rice balls out of the extra rice
There's also tempura, soft boiled eggs, and pickled vegetables
Thank you so much
I really appreciate it
Thanks, Ray
See you soon
Have a good night
Good night
That night
As I walked home after a wonderful meal with my friends
The day's events swirled through my mind
It was impossible for me to sleep
So I stayed up solving Shogi problems for most of the night
Until suddenly
The smell of the water and the sound of the river's waves hitting against the embankment
Climbed up to my room on the sixth floor
I have a question for you
Just like he asked me
I too want to be able to ask someone I look up to for advice
For advice
Someday
The scenery reflected in those eyes
The things that exist on the other side of the storm
Yes
I still don't know what stories are left once you've made it to the top
Who knows what happens then
What happens then?
Um...
Don't you think...
Isn't it about time for us to have dinner?
Oh...
Yeah...
I...
I don't think I've ever seen Hina quite this nervous before
Normally
She's bright and cheerful like a burst of light
Or as down as a dark cloud
Or angry like a bolt of lightning
But she's always lively
That's probably one of the best things about her
But right now
She's as stiff as a board
The reason for that
Takahashi is sitting right in front of her
Hina's big crush
Man, it feels like I haven't been here in forever
Not since second grade
Uh, Hina, are you okay?
I wanna have curry!
Right now, please!
Come on, Hina, get a grip
Do you think this'll be enough rice for him?
Was curry really the right thing to make?
Maybe I should've tried to make something fancier tonight
Curry is way too ordinary
He needs something more original
Something unique to satisfy him
You're worrying too much
It all came out great
I just got a message from Takahashi
He wants to know if I'm free Saturday
Do you think we could come hang out at your place?
Oof!
You know, maybe inviting him over wasn't the best idea after all
You're not going to be home Saturday night!
How could you do this to me?
That's what Takahashi's coming over!
That is a problem
Hmm, you do know I have to work at the club this Saturday
Let's see
I know!
Why don't you make him some curry?
I'll help you make it in advance
And then you can just warm it up when he gets here
That should work
See? You won't have to worry about messing up
Woah, that's way too normal!
It's gotta be fancier than that!
Something more elaborate!
Something with a wealth factor!
I can't believe you haven't learned your lesson yet!
Did you forget what happened with the lunch you made?
Look, you have to know!
Dinner must be planned!
Wait a minute, she just said dinner, didn't she?
Yeah, that is definitely what I heard her say!
What have I done?
I shouldn't say dinner when I'm talking about dinner!
Darn it, I just said dinner again when I didn't think to!
Dinner? Are you making our dinner?
Are you?
Now, how about adding a fried chicken topping?
Fried chicken, huh?
And what if we added a soft-boiled egg on top of that?
What do you think?
We can add a soft-boiled egg too?
Heck yeah!
Good, looks like that's settled
But, what about Takahashi?
Wow!
It even has a soft-boiled egg!
Thank you for the meal!
Wow!
He even eats just like a pro-athlete!
That was awesome, Hinata!
The fried chicken alone was great!
And there was an egg on top!
Talk about fancy food!
It was like eating at a restaurant!
Really?
You can have seconds too?
Yes!
Thank you, Akari!
Oh yeah, that's right!
There's something I want to talk to Kiriyama about!
Hinata, is it alright if I borrow your VCR?
Yeah, sure you can!
Oh!
And...
Um...
It should be here.
Serious!
It's the guy who it was your last time!
Wha-why is that?
Wait, really?
You mean Nikaido's been over here too?
No way!
But...
That's incredible!
He never said anything to us about ever being on TV!
Whoa.
He didn't?
Thought he was your best friend, Kiriyama.
Best friends?!
Why do people keep saying that about us?!
You two are supposed to be pretty close.
Nikaido says that all the time in interviews and stuff.
Wait a second.
If Nikaido was the one commentating...
Hey, why don't we save this video for the next time?
Black, gold to 6-6.
White, 3-4 bishop plus.
Black, dragon horse to 6-4.
Kiriyama, fifth den has seven minutes left.
Well, uh...
Thank you for dinner.
Ray, what are you doing on TV?
I thought you were going to show me.
You're too heavy.
Aw, shoot. Guess I blew it.
Crap. I didn't know Kiriyama was keeping it a secret.
Huh? What's going on?
Looks like your secret's out.
Oh, hello. Great to see you.
Well, if it isn't Takahashi-san, hey, you've gotten big.
How are your old man and granddad doing these days?
Good.
They're both well, sir.
They were fighting over Shogi again last night.
Uh, so, uh...
They wanted me to ask Kiriyama, fifth den a question.
Oh, it's the NHK cup.
So which part? I was watching it, too.
Oh, this one.
Black, Dragon Horse to 4-2.
What do you think you're doing, Kiriyama?
I have no idea if you went in for the killer to be killed with that move.
Now that's a truly passionate commentary.
My dad and grandpa both agreed.
They were saying they didn't think that one move was the losing move.
They just couldn't figure out why Nikaido 4-2 was getting so riled up over it.
Same king. Black, Gold, General to 5-5.
Actually, Nikaido was right.
That move was what caused me to lose the match.
My dad and grandpa didn't think that move was really all that bad.
In fact, they said it felt like an aggressive move fitting of a young man.
My opponent had me surrounded waiting for me to make a mistake, and I had nowhere to go.
I thought, let's find out if moving this piece over here will be a mistake or not.
Don't try to act cool, Kiriyama!
If you really want to win, stick it out!
Don't just attack, you've got to defend!
Why the hell have you been acting so weird lately?
Mr. Nikaido, we can't see the board!
You used to be so much more careful and determined back in the 3rd Den League.
You may be braver now, but it's made you overconfident and reckless, and you know it!
Please, you've got to calm down!
Do you hear me, Kiriyama?
I don't understand! You're too close to the camera, please!
Just play your own style of shogi!
Hey, you're better than this and you know it, Kiriyama!
The Kato 4th Den are playing on the 4th floor!
Don't you understand?
He can't hear you. I have to say this is highly unusual!
Hmm. I hope you're listening, kid.
You've got a true-blue friend there who's really looking out for you.
Yeah, wish I had friends like that.
I'm only telling you this because we're best friends!
You're best friend, he says!
Ha-ha-ha! Youth, I'm jealous! All that energy!
Oh, no!
I don't know!
Now listen! This is important!
Uh, I'm only gonna say this once!
In fact, I want you to get this on videotape and watch it over again and again!
Oh, listen to that!
Spoken like a true best friend.
You've got to take better care of yourself!
You're not making better progress because you don't do that!
Damn it! What do you know?
Who the hell do you think you are?
You're messing me up, damn it!
Hooray!
Well, look at that! The kid is angry!
What he's saying doesn't even make any sense!
I'm only gonna say this once, so record it and watch it over and over!
I don't even know what anything he says means!
That's a good point.
But I think Nikaido really does see you as his best friend.
He really cares about you a lot.
Wow! You guys are sweet and sour!
There is still some hope for this generation after all!
That was great!
Huh? What was so great?
That was unexpected, Rei! You've never raised your voice!
That wasn't what I expected.
What she said actually surprised me.
I want to learn! Shoggy looks fun!
After all, no one's ever said that to me before.
How could I respond?
Do you think it would be alright if you taught me how to play?
Would it be alright if you taught me how to play?
What a surprise!
No one had ever been that interested in my world before.
It made me feel so happy.
It was like swimming to shore for the first time.
And with every breath, I felt even better.
Maybe a plastic mat instead of a wooden board, since we'll probably be playing on the tea table in the living room.
Maybe she should use these plastic pieces.
They'll be easier for her to handle.
Momo does often spill milk on the table.
The characters won't wear off, so they'll be easy to read.
Oh, and maybe a guide with pictures will help out too.
I wonder, which one should I get?
If you're looking for textbooks for a beginner, I can give you my recommendations.
Mikaido?
Darn, they're sold out of that one.
How unfortunate.
Um, I'll take this, please.
You go, Kiriyama!
You sense the importance of spreading the word, too!
Sparkle, sparkle!
So, who are you teaching?
Wow!
Thank you for all of your help!
Yeah!
It's my pleasure!
No problem!
Okay, here goes.
I hope I'll be able to remember everything.
Don't even worry!
It may look like it's hard to learn, but it's actually not that difficult when you first start out.
If you do have trouble, just know that it's not your fault.
It's your teacher that's fully responsible for how well you do and how well you learn, not you.
And on that note...
Over to you, Mr. Kiriyama!
Go get him!
It's my turn after leading like that?
Come on!
All right, I'll try to keep this as simple as I can.
On this board with nine rows and nine columns, you and your opponent will each control 20 pieces that come in eight different types.
You take turns getting each other's pieces with the objective of capturing the opponent's king.
The person that's dubbed as black goes first, followed by the person playing as white, and then you continue going back and forth.
Each of the eight types of pieces has its own attributes and range of movement.
Also, the columns are called files and the rows are called ranks.
Each column is numbered, as well as each row.
Based on those numbers, all the boxes have addresses.
Next, we'll learn about how each piece moves across the board.
Kiriyama, slow down!
Relax! You're too stiff, man!
Look at her expression! She feels overwhelmed!
Maybe this is too hard for me.
You're gonna end up making her so nervous she won't get it!
It'll all just go in one ear and out the other!
You don't want to blow this chance!
Her first impression has to be that it's easy to play!
Okay, fine! Then what do you think I should do?
All right! Listen up, ladies!
It's my turn to teach you about Shogi!
Hey! Let's look at this picture book together!
All right!
Meow-meow!
Look, you kitty cat!
There's also a king!
And all kinds of kitties!
Shogi is a board game in which you use eight different types of pieces.
Each of them has its own personality.
You win the game by capturing your opponent's king.
You play on a board with 81 squares, 9 rows, and 9 columns.
The three rows closest to you are your land.
And the three rows on the other side are your opponent's land.
Next, I'll introduce the personalities and abilities of each type of cat on the board.
Daddy! I can't wait!
Great! Let's continue!
Nikaido!
Why are you so good at this?
What is this strange feeling I have?
Wow, really? No way! That's amazing!
What the heck?!
Young Master, this is lovely!
Ah, Nikardo! You're one of the few good ones!
I think I'm crying! I'm surprised you even noticed!
My pawpads is gonna not do silly!
Watch the next march comes in like a lion!
Shogi is so much fun! Let's all try it together!
...